A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Officers' Diaries xFA118
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Pearce, Richard M.
  - 1925 (Reel M Pea 2, Frame 275, Box 368)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and cooperation with medical schools in the development of programs for improving their facilities. The diary includes investigations of the status of medical education programs, emergency assistance in Europe and aid in medical school development.
    Public health; Medical education; Italy; Belgium; France; Algeria; Diaries; Hygiene; Nursing; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1925 Exhibits (Box 368)
    Scope and Contents notes
    The 1925 exhibits focus on scholars, resident fellows and equipment allowances, conference plans.
    Public health; Medical education; Belgium; Italy; Algeria; France; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - Haiti and San Domingo, 1925 (Box 368)
    The diary focuses on a trip to Haiti and San Domingo with training of men through Rockefeller Foundation fellowships, survey local medical schools, hospitals and nursing.
    Dominican Republic; Haiti; Public health; Diaries; Medical education; Nursing; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1926 (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 472)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and cooperation with medical schools in the development of programs for improving their facilities.
    Medical education; United States; Public health; Nursing; Diaries; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1926 Exhibits (Box 368)
    The 1926 exhibits include Sao Proldem, Conferences and Interviews with Prince Mahidol Songkla.
    Hospitals; Public health; United States; Medical education; Medical colleges; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1927 January 3- May 31 (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 674)
    Hospitals; Medical colleges; Public health; Diaries; Medical education; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1927 June 3-December 30 (Box 369, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 826)
    United States; Medical colleges; Hospitals; Medical education; Diaries; Public health; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1927 Exhibits (Box 369)
    The 1927 exhibits include a conference on Far Eastern matters was held on Monday March 28, 1927, RF medical education in Asia and public health.
    Public health; Hygiene; Nursing; China; Korea; Japan; East Asia; Medical education; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1928 January 6-May 28 (Box 369, Reel M Pea 3, Frame 1)
    The grants, visit and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on assistance in medical education, nursing education, miscellaneous activities in the medicine and biology. Pearce travels to Europe to survey medical education, assistance in improving research and teaching, and fellowship support.
    France; Medical education; Croatia; England; Diaries; Belgium; Public health; Hygiene; Nursing; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1928 May 29-December 31 (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 137, Box 369)
    The grants, visit and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on assistance in medical education, nursing education, miscellaneous activities in the medicine and biology. The diary surveys medical education, assistance in improving research and teaching, and fellowship support.
    Nursing; Hygiene; Public health; Medical education; Diaries; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1928 Exhibits (Box 369)
    Exhibits in connection with the 1928 diary concerning medical education, hygiene, nursing and public health.
    France; Diaries; Belgium; United States; Public health; Nursing; Croatia; England; Hygiene; Medical education; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1929 (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 262, Box 369)
    The Rockefeller Foundation Division of Medical Education reorganizes to become the Division of Medical Sciences. The mission changes from assisting countries with advancements in medical education to a policy in which research and the advancement of knowledge in medical sciences is considered the principle interest.
    Medical sciences; Diaries; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Pearce, Richard Mills
  - 1929 Exhibits (Box 369)
    Exhibits in connection with the 1929 diary concerning medical sciences, hygiene and public health.
    Medical sciences; Public health; United States; Hygiene; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences
  - 1930 (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 442, Box 369)
    A brief diary of Rockefeller Foundation work in Medical Sciences before his death on February 16, 1930.
    Diaries; United States; Hygiene; Medical sciences; Public health; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Pearce, Richard Mills
- Peck, Marshall
  - 1967-1969 (Box 370)
- Perry, Jesse P.
  - 1960-1961 (Box 370)
  - 1960 July-September (Box 370)
  - 1960 October-December (Box 370)
  - 1961 (Box 370)
  - 1962 January-May (Box 370)
  - 1962 May-June (Box 371)
  - 1962 July-September (Box 371)
  - 1962 October-December (Box 371)
  - 1963 January-May 1 (Box 371)
  - 1963 May-June (Box 371)
  - 1963 July-November 1 (Box 372)
  - 1963 November 4-December (Box 372)
  - 1964 January (Box 372)
  - 1964 February (Box 372)
  - 1964 March (Box 372)
  - 1964 April-May (Box 372)
  - 1964 June (Box 372)
  - 1964 July-August (Box 372)
  - 1964 September (Box 373)
  - 1964 October (Box 373)
  - 1964 November (Box 373)
  - 1964 December (Box 373)
  - 1965 January-June (Box 373)
  - 1965 March-April (Box 373)
  - 1965 May (Box 373)
  - 1965 June (Box 373)
  - 1965 July (Box 373)
  - 1965 August-September (Box 373)
  - 1965 October (Box 373)
  - 1965 November-December (Box 373)
  - 1966 January (Box 373)
  - 1966 February-April (Box 374)
  - 1966 May-June (Box 374)
  - 1966 July-August (Box 374)
  - 1966 September-October (Box 374)
  - 1966 November-December (Box 374)
  - 1967 January (Box 374)
  - 1967 February-May (Box 374)
  - 1967 June-August (Box 374)
  - 1967 September-October (Box 374)
  - 1967 November-December (Box 374)
  - 1968 January-February (Box 374)
  - 1968 March-May (Box 374)
  - 1968 June-September (Box 375)
  - 1968 October-December (Box 375)
  - 1969 January-February (Box 375)
  - 1969 March-April (Box 375)
  - 1969 May-July (Box 375)
  - 1969 August-December (Box 375)
  - 1970 (Box 375)
  - 1970 (Box 375)
  - 1971 January-August (Box 375)
  - 1971 September-December (Box 375)
  - 1972 January-April (Box 375)
  - 1972 May-December (Box 376)
  - 1973 (Box 376)
  - 1974 (Box 376)
- Peterson, Osler L.
  - 1945 (Box 376)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 376)
  - 1948 (Box 376)
  - 1949 (Box 376)
  - 1950 (Box 376)
  - 1951 (Box 376)
  - 1952 (Box 376)
  - 1953-1955 (Box 376)
  - 1956 January-September (Box 377)
  - 1956 October-December (Box 377)
  - 1957 January-March (Box 377)
  - 1957 April-July (Box 377)
  - 1957 August-December (Box 377)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 377)
  - 1958 May-December (Box 377)
  - 1959 (Box 377)
- Pino, John A.
  - 1965 July-1966 February (Box 378)
  - 1966 March-June (Box 378)
  - 1966 July-December (Box 378)
  - 1967 January-March (Box 378)
  - 1967 April-July (Box 378)
  - 1967 August-December (Box 378)
  - 1968 (Box 379)
  - 1969 (Box 379)
  - 1970 (Box 380)
  - 1971 (Box 380)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 380)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 381)
  - 1977-1980 (Box 381)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 382)
  - 1983 (Box 382)
  - Index (Box 382)
- Plank, Stephen J.
  - 1973-1975 (Box 382)
- Pomerat, Gerald R.
  - 1946 March-May (Box 383)
  - 1946 June-August (Box 383)
  - 1946 September-December (Box 383)
  - 1947 January-April (Box 383)
  - 1947 May-July (Box 383)
  - 1947 August-December (Box 383)
  - 1948 January-April (Box 383)
  - 1948 May-September (Box 383)
  - 1948 October-December (Box 383)
  - 1949 January-April (Box 384)
  - 1949 May-June (Box 384)
  - 1949 July-December (Box 384)
  - 1950 January-May (Box 384)
  - 1950 June-September (Box 384)
  - 1950 October-December (Box 384)
  - 1951 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1951 May-August (Box 385)
  - 1951 September-December (Box 385)
  - 1952 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1952 April-June (Box 385)
  - 1952 July-December (Box 385)
  - 1953 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1953 April-June (Box 385)
  - 1953 July-December (Box 385)
  - 1954 January-April 9 (Box 386)
  - 1954 April 10-May 28 (Box 386)
  - 1954 May 31-December (Box 386)
  - 1955 January-April 29 (Box 386)
  - 1955 April 29-May (Box 386)
  - 1955 June-October 31 (Box 386)
  - 1955 October 31-December (Box 386)
  - 1956 January-May 6 (Box 387)
  - 1956 May 7-June (Box 387)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 387)
  - 1957 January-May 16 (Box 387)
  - 1957 May 17-August 2 (Box 387)
  - 1957 August 6-December (Box 387)
  - Hungary, 1956 (Box 387)
  - Hungary, 1957 (Box 387)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 388)
  - 1958 May (Box 388)
  - 1958 June (Box 388)
  - 1958 July-December (Box 388)
  - 1959 January-April (Box 388)
  - 1959 May (Box 388)
  - 1959 June-July (Box 388)
  - 1959 August-December (Box 388)
  - 1960 January-April (Box 389)
  - 1960 May (Box 389)
  - 1960 June-July (Box 389)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 389)
  - 1961 April-October (Box 389)
  - 1961 November-December (Box 389)
  - 1962 January-May (Box 390)
  - 1962 June-August (Box 390)
  - 1962 September-December (Box 390)
  - 1963 January-April (Box 390)
  - 1963 May-August (Box 390)
  - 1963 September-December (Box 390)
  - 1964 January-April (Box 390)
  - 1964 May-June (Box 390)
  - 1964 July-December (Box 390)
  - Far East (Duplicate), 1965 (Box 391)
  - 1965 January-May (Box 391)
  - 1965 July-December (Box 391)
  - 1966 January-June (Box 391)
  - 1966 August-December (Box 391)
  - 1967 (Box 391)
  - Diary Indexes, 1946-1954 (Box 391)
  - Diary Indexes, 1955-1967 (Box 391)
- Prager, June
  - Theatre Diary, 1980-1981 (Box 392)
- Prentice, Michael
  - 1973-1978 (Box 392)
- Read, Elsmer R.
  - 1941-1946 (Box 393)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 393)
- Read, Florence M.
  - 1920-1927 (Box 393)
- Rhind, Flora
  - 1948-1956 (Box 394)
- Richardson, Ralph W.
  - 1956 October-November (Box 394)
  - 1959 August-1960 February (Box 394)
  - 1960 March-July (Box 394)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 394)
  - 1961 January-July (Box 394)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 394)
  - 1962 January-February (Box 395)
  - 1962 March-May (Box 395)
  - 1962 June-October (Box 395)
  - 1962 November-December (Box 395)
  - 1963 January-February (Box 395)
  - 1963 March-May (Box 395)
  - 1963 June-July (Box 395)
  - 1963 August-December (Box 395)
  - 1964 January-May (Box 396)
  - 1964 June-September (Box 396)
  - 1964 October-December (Box 396)
  - 1965 January-September (Box 397)
  - 1965 June-July (Box 397)
  - 1965 August-September (Box 397)
  - 1965 October-December (Box 397)
  - 1966 January-February (Box 398)
  - 1966 March-April (Box 398)
  - 1966 May-June (Box 398)
  - 1966 July-September (Box 398)
  - 1966 October-December (Box 398)
  - 1967 January-June (Box 399)
  - 1967 July-September (Box 399)
  - 1967 October-December (Box 399)
  - 1968 January-May (Box 399)
  - 1968 June-December (Box 399)
  - 1969 January-October (Box 400)
  - 1969 October-December (Box 400)
  - Index, Diary, 1970 January-February (Box 401)
  - 1970 March-April (Box 401)
  - 1970 May-August (Box 401)
  - 1970 September-October (Box 401)
  - 1970 November-December (Box 401)
  - 1971 January (Box 401)
  - 1971 February-March (Box 401)
  - 1971 April (Box 401)
  - 1971 May-June (Box 402)
  - 1971 July-August (Box 402)
  - 1971 September-December (Box 402)
  - 1972 (Box 402)
  - 1973 (Box 403)
  - 1974 (Box 403)
  - 1975 (Box 403)
  - 1976 (Box 403)
  - 1977 (Box 404)
  - 1978-1980 (Box 404)
  - Index, 1962-1970 (Box 404)
- Ritcher, Paul O.
  - 1958-1959 (Box 404)
- Robbins, William J.
  - 1929-1930 (Box 405)
    See also Wilbur E. Tisdale and E. W. Lindstrom, May 1928-January 1929.
- Roberts, Lewis M.
  - 1952-1955 August (Box 405)
  - 1955 September-1957 (Box 405)
  - 1958 (Box 405)
  - 1960 January-March (Box 406)
  - 1960 April-August (Box 406)
  - 1960 September-December (Box 406)
  - 1961 January-April (Box 406)
  - 1961 May-July (Box 406)
  - 1961 August-December (Box 406)
  - 1962 January-April (Box 407)
  - 1962 May-August 2 (Box 407)
  - 1962 August 3-October (Box 407)
  - 1962 November-December (Box 407)
  - 1963 January-February (Box 408)
  - 1963 March-May (Box 408)
  - 1963 June-September (Box 408)
  - 1963 October-December (Box 408)
  - 1964 January-March (Box 409)
  - 1964 April-June (Box 409)
  - 1964 July-October (Box 409)
  - 1964 November-December (Box 409)
  - 1965 January-April (Box 409)
  - 1965 May-September (Box 409)
  - 1965 October-December (Box 409)
  - 1966 January-February (Box 410)
  - 1966 March-May (Box 410)
  - 1966 June-September (Box 410)
  - 1966 October-December (Box 410)
  - 1967 January-March (Box 410)
  - 1967 April-August (Box 410)
  - 1967 September-October (Box 410)
  - 1967 November-December (Box 410)
  - 1968 (Box 411)
  - 1969 (Box 411)
  - 1970 (Box 412)
  - 1971 (Box 412)
  - 1972 (Box 412)
  - 1973 (Box 413)
  - Trips to Honduras, Guatamala, 1973 December (Box 413)
  - 1974 January-August (Box 413)
  - Trips to Amazon, 1964, 1969, 1971, 1977 (Box 413)
- Robertson, William van B.
  - 1967 (Box 413)
- Rogers, Thomas E.
  - 1964-1966 (Box 414)
- Rohde, Jon E.
  - 1973-1976 (Box 414)
  - 1977 (Box 414)
- Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1911 Rockefeller Sanitary Commission - Itineraries of the Administrative Secretary (Box 415, Reel M Ros 1, Frame 1)
    Rose reports on county dispensaries in Marion county, Mississippi and Alabama.
    United States; Dispensaries; Mississippi; Sanitation; Hygiene; Rural population; Hookworm disease; Alabama; Public health; Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1911 Itinerary of the Administrative Secretary though Northern Neck, Viriginia, June 1911
    Rose reports on hookworm disease in Northern Neck, Virginia.
    United States; Virginia; Hookworm disease; Sanitation; Public health; Rural population; Hygiene; Dispensaries; Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1911 Itinerary of the Administrative Secretary through Columbus, Robeson, Sampson and Halifax Counties, North Carolina, July 1911
    Hygiene; Dispensaries; North Carolina; United States; Sanitation; Hookworm disease; Rural population; Public health; Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1912 Itinerary of the Administrative Secretary through Bell county, Kentucky, October 1912
    Kentucky; United States; Sanitation; Hookworm disease; Rural population; Public health; Dispensaries; Hygiene; Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1913 International Health Commission - Notes on the Journey to England and the West Indies (Reel M Ros 1, Frame 58, Box 415)
    Hookworm disease; Sanitation; England; West Indies; Barbados; Grenada; Saint Lucia; Saint Vincent; Trinidad; Antigua; Public health; Hygiene; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1914 Itinerary of the Director General through the Federation Malay States, May 1914 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 1, Frame 131)
    Rose travels to the Federated Malay States to survey government and estate hospitals, and determine the present efforts to combat hookworm disease. The diary includes itinerary through the Philippine Islands.
    Malaysia; Philippines; Hookworm disease; Public health; Sanitation; Hygiene; Malaria; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1914 Diary Notes
    The diary includes notes on trips to England and Egypt; program of relief, control and prevention of Hookworm disease in Sri Lanka; notes on the malaria program, and notes on sanitation and hookworm disease in Malay and survey conditions in the Philippines.
    Malaria; Sanitation; Tropical medicine; Venereal diseases; Public health; Japan; Hookworm disease; United States; Singapore; Malaysia; Sri Lanka; Egypt; England; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1915 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 1, Frame 190)
    The diary documents an interview regarding disease prevention in Turkey.
    Medicine, Preventive; Hookworm disease; Hygiene; Malaria; Public health; Sanitation; Turkey; United States; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1916 The Situation in Mexico and the Possibilities of Cooperation with the International Health Board (Box 415, Reel M Ros 1, Frame 235)
    The diary documents a conference held with Senior Cabrera of Mexico to discuss cooperation with Rockefeller Foundation to help control Typhus Fever in Mexico.
    Malaria; Public health; Yellow fever; Hookworm disease; Mexico; Hygiene; Sanitation; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1917 Conference with Peter Goldsmith, January 29, 1917 (Reel M Ros 1, Frame 244, Box 415)
    In an interview with Goldsmith, he discusses his travels to South America as a representative of the Department of Education and Intercourse of the Carnegie Foundation for Peace to survey their local education and establish personal relations with leaders of public opinion.
    Sanitation; Public health; Hygiene; South America; United States; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1918 Conferences in Washington (Box 415, Reel M Ros 1, Frame 248)
    Agriculture; United States; Hygiene; Sanitation; Public health; Yellow fever; Tuberculosis; Malaria; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1919 (Reel M Ros 1, Frame 295, Box 415)
    The IHB cooperates with governments throughout the world in demonstrating the feasibility and economic value of preventive measures against disease and creating popular interest and support for public health work. The diary documents the campaign against Tuberculosis in France, Malaria work in Italy and manufacturing oil of chenopodium.
    Agriculture; Sanitation; Hygiene; Public health; Jaundice; Nursing; United States; Europe; Communicable diseases; Hookworm disease; France; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - Index, 1920 (Reel M Ros 2, Frame 1, Box 415)
    1920 Index; 4 pages
    Holland (Netherlands: Province); France; Europe; South America; Belgium; Public health; Sanitation; Hygiene; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1920 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 2, Frame 5)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of public health focus on prevention of disease. The diary includes updates on International Health Board projects, malaria control through quinine, discussions of effects of World War I and a conference between Dr. Heiser and Dr. Rose regarding South America.
    Hygiene; Sanitation; Tropical medicine; Public health; Medicine, Preventive; Medical education; Medicine; Malaria; World War I; Belgium; Dispensaries; Tuberculosis; Europe; South America; Holland (Netherlands: Province); France; Nursing; Communicable diseases; Yellow fever; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - Index, 1921 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 2, Frame 152)
    1921 Index; 9 pages
    Sanitation; Hygiene; United States; Public health; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1921 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 2, Frame 161)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of public health focus on prevention of disease through new national health services and new ministries of health. The diary also documents yellow fever discussions.
    Tuberculosis; Hookworm disease; Tropical medicine; Malaria; United States; Hygiene; Sanitation; Yellow fever; Public health; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - Index, 1922-1923 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 2, Frame 412)
  - 1922 (Box 415, Reel M Ros 2, Frame 418)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of public health focus on prevention of disease.
    Public health; Yellow fever; Hygiene; Sanitation; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1923-1924 Index
    1923-1924 Index; 6 pages
    Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Commission
  - 1922 Index Log of Journey to Europe
    Index Log of Journey to Europe; 5 pages
    Europe; Hygiene; Tropical medicine; Public health; Sanitation; Malaria; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
  - 1922 Diary, Including Log of Journey to Europe (Reel M Ros 2, Frame 438, Box 415)
    Diary Log of Journey to Europe- Includes memorandum of visits and malaria survey in Italy.
    England; Ireland; Sanitation; Public health; Tropical medicine; Hygiene; Malaria; Italy; Europe; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
  - 1922 5 May- 30 December
    This diary of Wickliffe Rose documents a trip to London and includes various updates on International Health Board programs.
    Malaria; Tropical medicine; Hygiene; Yellow fever; Public health; Sanitation; United States; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
  - 1923-1924 Index
    Index of countries and Cities Visited and of Institutions and Organizations Mentioned in Log; 12 pages
    Hygiene; Public health; Sanitation; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board; Rose, Wickliffe
  - 1923 December- 1924 April (Reel M Ros 2, Frame 741, Box 416)
    Index of Names of Persons Mentioned; 6 pages. Itinerary from December 1923- April 1924 in connection with work of the International Education Board. The diary surveys agricultural education and research laboratories in Europe.
    France; Scotland; Ireland; England; Europe; Poland; Germany; Denmark; Czechoslovakia; Austria; Hungary; Yugoslavia; Bulgaria; Italy; Switzerland; Spain; Norway; Sweden; Belgium; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Education; Agriculture; Rose, Wickliffe; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Board
- Rupert, Joseph A.
  - 1955-1957 (Box 417)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 417)
  - Diary Duplicate, 1959 (Box 417)
  - 1960-1962, 1964, 1966 (Box 417)
- Rusk, Dean
  - 1952-1960 (Box 417)
- Russell, Frederick F.
  - 1922-1924 (Box 417)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 418)
  - 1927-1930 (Box 418)
  - 1931-1935 (Box 418)
- Russell, Harry Luman
  - Vol. I: Japan, 1925-1926 (Box 419)
  - Vol. II: China and Philippines, 1926 (Box 419)
  - Vol. III: Siam, Java, Australia, 1926 (Box 420)
  - Vol. IV: New Zealand, Hawaii, Summary, and Index of Orient Trip, 1926 (Box 420)
- Russell, Paul F.
  - 1938 (Box 421, Reel M Rus 1, Frame 1)
    In the 1938 diary of Russell, he investigates and researches Malaria in his Madras laboratory. The bulk of the diary includes his daily research measurements of mosquito densities. An experiment research report is included.
    Malaria; India; Diaries; Public health; Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Russell, Paul F.
  - 1939 (Box 421, Reel M Rus 1, Frame 72)